<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Resumé</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="title">Justin Katzwhite\'s Resumé</string>
    <string name="email">jkatzwhitew@gmail.com</string>

    <string name="retrieve">Retrieve data from cloud </string>
    <string name="clear">Clear SQLite Database</string>

    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="BI">Background Information</string>
    <string name="background">Background</string>
    <string name="skills">Skills</string>
    <string name="PL">Programming Languages</string>
    <string name="C">Contact</string>
    <string name="S">SQL</string>
    <string name="tastebudz">Tastebudz</string>

    <string name="PL_textview">
        This view is scrollable.

        \n\nPress a view to insert app data into SQLite database. Long press a view to
        retrieve data from cloud database and insert into SQLite database. Either way you will be able to
        learn about my experience with its associated language(s).

        \n\nTo delete database entries, select settings on the top right and select "Clear SQLite Database."
        You can then retrieve current entries by pressing the view associated with the language.
    </string>

    <string name="contact">
        \nIf you would like to contact me, please send an e-mail to the e-mail
        address provided below. I should respond within 48 hours. Thank you.</string>

    <string-array name="skill_titles">
        <item>Android</item>
        <item>Cloud</item>
        <item>Firebase</item>
        <item>IDE</item>
        <item>OS</item>
        <item>Github</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="programming_languages">
        <item>
            I’ve been programming in Java and developing Android applications for over three
            years.

            \n\nI’ve developed android apps that use activities, fragments, layouts,
            adapters, classes, client libraries designed to communicate with backend APIs,
            LRUcache, SQLite and navigation drawers. These apps have used the camera and nfc
            adapter in smartphones. I\'ve also used Firebase services such as crashlytics,
            authentication and uploading images.</item>

        <item>
            I’ve designed backend APIs in Python that communicate with frontend client applications
            using JSON. I\'m familiar with OAuth2.0.</item>

        <item>
            I’ve designed cloud applications in Python supported by Google App Engine (GAE). These
            applications use the webapp2 framework and the Jinja template.

            \n\nI’ve also created NoSQL databases that supply data to the web application and the
            backend API. I’ve used cloud applications to transmit various data including text, image
            urls and prices.</item>

        <item>
            I’ve created web applications using HTML5, JavaScript and CSS and have had these
            applications interact with the cloud applications I’ve created.

            \n\nBy interacting, data could be submitted to the cloud database and retrieved as well.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="java_text">
        I started learning and programming in Java in the end of 2014. In early 2015 I started developing Android apps
        in Java. I’ve developed a strong understanding of the Android framework including activities, fragments,
        layouts and views. As well as more advanced features such as adapters, client libraries designed to communicate
        with backend APIs, SQLite databases and navigation drawers. Because of my work on Tastebudz, I’ve developed a
        very strong understanding of the nfc adapter found in Android powered smartphones.

        In keeping up the latest technology, I’ve worked software included in Android Jetpack such as ViewModel,
        RecylcerView, LiveData and Room.

        Some of the apps I've developed use Google Play Services such as Google Maps.

        I test many of the Android apps I develop using jUnit and Espresso.
    </string>

    <string name="kotlin_text">
        I started developing Android apps in Kotlin in the beginning of 2019. Learning the change in syntax and
        structure required some patience but now I’ve come to appreciate the simplicity that Kotlin was intended to
        provide. I’m still learning the intricacies of Kotlin but I’m getting better every day. In fact, this entire
        app is written in Kotlin.
    </string>

    <string name="python_text">
        I started programming in Python in the middle of 2015. Eager to learn about cloud computing and how a mobile
        app interacted with a cloud backend, I started working on example projects on Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
        Recently, I’ve migrated from Python 2 to Python 3.

        I leverage many of Python’s features. I use pip for downloading packages. I have a very strong understanding
        of data models such as dictionaries. I leverage many of Python’s built-in functions and can implement newer
        technology such as lambda functions.

        I practice good testing habits and test many of my Python scripts using PyTest.
    </string>

    <string name="gcp_text">
        I’ve been developing Python apps hosted on GCP since 2015. Starting with Cloud SDK, I’ve have used many programs
        that come with the package such as dev_server, endpointscfg, appcfg. Before uploading my app to App Engine, I
        would test it using dev_server. This is how quickly learned many APIs.

        I’ve worked with Datastore, Google’s NoSql database; Memcache, for storing tokens; creating my own endpoints,
        the Requests API and Stackdriver.

        Recently I’ve learned about concurrency by using Python’s asyncio. I’ve also learned about kubernetes, compute
        engine, cloud functions, big query and big table.
    </string>

    <string name="aws_text">
        I have some experience with AWS. While I’m not as familiar with it as GCP, I’m learning more about the features
        it has to offer.
    </string>

    <string name="firebase_text">
        I started working with Firebase in the middle of 2017. Looking to add messaging and profiles to Tastebudz, I
        started learning about the features Firebase had to offer. I linked my GCP project to Firebase and activated
        the messaging capability. I created a new endpoint in my backend for messaging and added the feature to
        Tastebudz.

        For the profiles, I created a new activity in the Tastebudz app and added an endpoint in my backend for
        registering profiles.

        I would later add a menu building activity in Tastebudz. To store the menu item images, I used Firebase
        storage, which linked with my project's cloud storage, and populated it with the images uploaded.

        To catch any errors that might occur while people were running Tastebudz, I included Firebase’s Crashlytics.
        Crashlytics catches errors and crashes and then sends an email to the project owners informing them about
        what happened. Crashlytics is a very useful tool for ensuring flawless performance.
    </string>

    <string name="studio_text">
        I\'ve been working with Android Studio since it came out in beta. Today, I have an excellent understanding of
        the IDE and leverage several features during development. I use Android Studio’s VCS capability to push daily
        improvements to the source code I work on. I use Gradle to synchronize the additional libraries and dependencies
        that each app uses. I test the apps I develop on smartphones as well as Android Studio’s emulator. I’m able to
        leverage Android Studio’s refactoring capability to quickly make changes across the source code. I use Logcat to
        track the events that occur while the app is running and Profiler to view how efficiently the app is running.
    </string>

    <string name="pycharm_text">
        I\'ve been using PyCharm since the middle of 2015. I use PyCharm to create python apps that are uploaded to GCP.
        After creating a virtual environment, I use pip to download GCP packages, write the code using these packages
        and test the scripts using dev_server provided by Cloud SDK
    </string>

    <string name="windows7_text">
        Before 2019, Windows was the only OS I had worked with. I had become very familiar with both command line and
        PowerShell. I also have technical experience with Microsoft Excel.
    </string>

    <string name="mint_text">
        Since the beginning of 2019 I\'ve been developing in a Linux environment. With Linux Mint as my distro,
        I\'ve picked up the terminal commands and have come to embrace the open source community.
    </string>

    <string name="github_text">
        I use git for my VCS and GitHub as my remote repository. I\'m capable of using git in both the command terminal
        and IDE. I have a GitHub account showcasing some of the work I've done. If you're interested, check out
        https://github.com/jak-jak18.
    </string>

    <string name="background_information">
        \nI\'ve been developing mobile apps since 2015.
        I spent a year learning and programming in multiple programming languages such as Java and Python.
        Now I\'m able to utilize technology essential to many different applications. I have two applications found
        on the Google Play Store.

        Tastebudz is an app I developed that is intended for the restaurant industry. By using the nfc adapter on
        customer\'s phone, customers can quickly scan an nfc tag and be paired with the restaurant\'s menu. This allows
        for digital ordering and many more features.

        In 2006 I enrolled in the University of Pittsburgh School of
        Engineering and in 2010 I received a B.S. in Electrical Engineering with a minor in
        mathematics. From my pursuit of a B.S., I\'ve learned to work effectively in a team setting.

        \n\nDuring my stay, I contributed to research studying Power Quality (PQ) events in power
        lines and power outlets.

        \n\nAfterwards, I worked for over 4 years at the United States Patent and Trademark Office.
        My daily activities included reviewing and prosecuting applications and arguing against and
        negotiating with patent attorneys. I worked at the GS-11 level.

    </string>
</resources>
