<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Resumé</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="title">Justin Katzwhite\'s Resumé</string>
    <string name="email">jkatzwhitew@gmail.com</string>

    <string name="retrieve">Retrieve data from cloud </string>
    <string name="clear">Clear SQLite Database</string>

    <string name="Home">Home</string>
    <string name="BI">Background Information</string>
    <string name="PL">Programming Languages</string>
    <string name="C">Contact</string>
    <string name="S">SQL</string>

    <string name="PL_textview">
        This view is scrollable.

        \n\nPress a view to insert app data into SQLite database. Long press a view to
        retrieve data from cloud database and insert into SQLite database. Either way you will be able to
        learn about my experience with its associated language(s).

        \n\nTo delete database entries, select settings on the top right and select "Clear SQLite Database."
        You can then retrieve current entries by pressing the view associated with the language.
        </string>

    <string name="contact">If you would like to contact me, please send an e-mail to the e-mail
        address provided below. I should respond within 48 hours. Thank you.</string>

    <string-array name="programming_languages">
        <item>
            I’ve been programming in Java and developing Android applications for over three
            years.

            \n\nI’ve developed android apps that use activities, fragments, layouts,
            adapters, classes, client libraries designed to communicate with backend APIs,
            LRUcache, SQLite and navigation drawers. These apps have used the camera and nfc
            adapter in smartphones. I\'ve also used Firebase services such as crashlytics,
            authentication and uploading images.</item>

        <item>
            I’ve designed backend APIs in Python that communicate with frontend client applications
            using JSON. I\'m familiar with OAuth2.0.</item>

        <item>
            I’ve designed cloud applications in Python supported by Google App Engine (GAE). These
            applications use the webapp2 framework and the Jinja template.

            \n\nI’ve also created NoSQL databases that supply data to the web application and the
            backend API. I’ve used cloud applications to transmit various data including text, image
            urls and prices.</item>

        <item>
            I’ve created web applications using HTML5, JavaScript and CSS and have had these
            applications interact with the cloud applications I’ve created.

            \n\nBy interacting, data could be submitted to the cloud database and retrieved as well.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="background_information">
        Currently, I\'m 30 years old. In 2006 I enrolled in the University of Pittsburgh School of
        Engineering and in 2010 I received a B.S. in Electrical Engineering with a minor in
        mathematics. From my pursuit of a B.S., I\'ve learned to work effectively in groups and have
        become much more innovative.

        \n\nDuring my stay, I contributed to research studying Power Quality (PQ) events in power
        lines and power outlets.

        \n\nAfterwards, I worked for over 4 years at the United States Patent and Trademark Office.
        My daily activities included reviewing and prosecuting applications and arguing against and
        negotiating with patent attorneys. I worked at the GS-11 level.

        \n\nAround the age of 26 I developed a curiosity in computer programming, specifically mobile app design.
        I spent a year learning and programming in multiple programming languages.
        Since, I\'ve been able to create various examples utilizing technology essential to many different applications.
    </string>

</resources>
